<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Concepts on Xeneta Guide</title>
    <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Concepts on Xeneta Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Freight Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/introfreightrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/introfreightrate/</guid>
      <description>What is a freight rate? A freight rate is a negotiated price for shipping a freight container from one part of the world to another.
Freight rates that are tied to contracts have a validity period that defines the length of time that the freight rate is valid. The validity of a freight rate will depend on if it is based on a short-term contract or a long-term contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Metrics</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/marketmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/marketmetrics/</guid>
      <description>For an in-depth look at Market Metrics, read our article in the help center. Market metrics are a set of options that control how freight rate data is displayed in Xeneta. You can think of them as a global-level filters for rate information.
They appear in the top-right corner of on any pages capable of showing freight data — including Air and Ocean dashboards.
 Currently, Xeneta uses 3 types of market metrics across both Ocean and Air freight products:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Horizon</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/futures/</guid>
      <description>At its core, the Xeneta platform helps you understand the trends in the freight market. It does so by providing three views of the market:
 The historical rate trends The current day&amp;rsquo;s rate The trends of rates that run into the future or begin in the future  In the third case, Xeneta offers a short view of the future by showing contracted freight rates that extend past the current day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>