<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Xeneta Guide</title>
    <link>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Xeneta Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/uploading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/uploading/</guid>
      <description>One of the core features of the Xeneta platform is the ability to benchmark your rates against the market. Benchmarking is another way of saying &amp;ldquo;comparing&amp;rdquo; — that is, you compare the prices you pay for shipping against other market participants as a whole.
Benchmarking can help you understand how much you pay relative to the market and can, in turn, give you the insight you need to negotiate better rates in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/gettingstarted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/gettingstarted/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s platform offers you a number of tools to help you understand the freight market. Here you can find some basic use cases for the Xeneta platform. Ocean View a summary of your freight ratesUse the dashboard to get an overview of your rates and how they compare to the market. Get a spot rate for a trade laneUse the trade lane search from the dashboard to retrieve today&amp;#39;s market rates for any origin and destination port across a number of container types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <link>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xveneta.net/introduction/reports/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta can create a number of Excel reports based on the analytics data found on our platform.
Any page capable of exporting an Excel report will contain a  symbol in the top-right corner of the page. You can find all your created reports on the Reports page.
Note: A number of larger reports will take some time to generate. In such cases, you&amp;rsquo;ll be notified by email when your report is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>