<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on Xeneta Guide</title>
    <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on Xeneta Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at using Xeneta to compare your uploaded freight rates to current and historical market rates. Introduction The Benchmarks graph is designed to help you compare your freight rates against the market. At its core, it plots Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s market benchmarks alongside your own freight rates.
The Benchmarks graph. The Benchmarks graph can be reached in two ways:
 Clicking the View Graph button from the dashboard search after searching for a trade lane or trade corridor Clicking the View Graph button from the Market Trends page if you have followed trade lanes  Filtering Your Data The Benchmark graph contains a number of filters to help you narrow the scope of the market such that you can compare your prices to the most relevant segments of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Excel for Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at working with Excel to look at Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s Benchmarking data by exploring a few basic examples. Introduction Xeneta can export the data that composes the Benchmarks graph to an Excel report.
To begin, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to generate the Benchmarks graph for the trade lane or trade corridor whose data we wish to export. Use the dashboard search or your followed trade lanes to reach the Benchmarks graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Rates Beyond Today</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the Contract Horizon feature to examine where the freight market is trending past the present day. Introduction The Xeneta platform provides market trends and benchmarks based on current and historical freight rates. Of course, in the cycle of freight procurement and contract negotiation, new shipping contracts are always being established.
In these cases, the contracts negotiated near the present day may be contracted to start a few weeks or months in the future — but they are still signed today and reflect today&amp;rsquo;s market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Market Metrics</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/marketmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/marketmetrics/</guid>
      <description>For an in-depth look at Market Metrics, read our article in the help center. Market metrics are a set of options that control how freight rate data is displayed in Xeneta. You can think of them as a global-level filters for rate information.
They appear in the top-right corner of on any pages capable of showing freight data — including Air and Ocean dashboards.
Market metrics for ocean freight.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>