<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xeneta Guide</title>
    <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xeneta Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guide.xeneta.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/intelligence/benchmarking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/intelligence/benchmarking/</guid>
      <description>Overview Benchmarking allows you to compare the prices you pay for ocean freight to the prices paid by the market. By knowing where you stand within the market, you can begin to make decisions about improving your procurement process.
The Xeneta platform has a number of tools for benchmarking your prices against the market.
Uploading Your Prices Before you can begin benchmarking, you will need to upload your prices to Xeneta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identify Market Disruptions</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/identify-market-disruptions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/identify-market-disruptions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Xeneta can visualize market movements with its graphing functionality. This is immediately useful for identifying how the market reacts to world events and gives you the insight to be proactive about your freight procurement.
Long-term vs. Short-term As an example, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at the trends of the past year between China East Main and the US West Coast from 12-10-2019  to 12-10-2020.
 View example in Xeneta  In the image above, we have plotted the short-term (yellow) and long-term (blue) market averages for the past year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at using Xeneta to compare your uploaded freight rates to current and historical market rates. Introduction The Benchmarks graph is designed to help you compare your freight rates against the market. At its core, it plots Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s market benchmarks alongside your own freight rates.
 The Benchmarks graph can be reached in two ways:
 Clicking the View Graph button from the dashboard search after searching for a trade lane or trade corridor Clicking the View Graph button from the Market Trends page if you have followed trade lanes  Filtering Your Data The Benchmark graph contains a number of filters to help you narrow the scope of the market such that you can compare your prices to the most relevant segments of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Freight Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/introfreightrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/introfreightrate/</guid>
      <description>What is a freight rate? A freight rate is a negotiated price for shipping a freight container from one part of the world to another.
Freight rates that are tied to contracts have a validity period that defines the length of time that the freight rate is valid. The validity of a freight rate will depend on if it is based on a short-term contract or a long-term contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/overview/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta for Air Freight is an analytics and benchmark platform for understanding the prices of the air freight market. The Dashboard For details about Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s benchmarking of air freight, read this article. Like the Ocean dashboard, the Air freight dashboard contains a location search bar and a summary of your price coverage and price benchmarks.
 The Location Search The location search on the dashboard is used to find spot rates for air freight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>Get an overview of Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s capabilities in this introductory guide.
1Search for a spot price  2View Market Prices  3View Your Uploaded Prices  4View Spend Overview 
1Search for a Spot Price  Navigate to the dashboard The Xeneta dashboard provides an overview of your uploaded rates and how the market compares to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Metrics</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/marketmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/marketmetrics/</guid>
      <description>For an in-depth look at Market Metrics, read our article in the help center. Market metrics are a set of options that control how freight rate data is displayed in Xeneta. You can think of them as a global-level filters for rate information.
They appear in the top-right corner of on any pages capable of showing freight data — including Air and Ocean dashboards.
 Currently, Xeneta uses 3 types of market metrics across both Ocean and Air freight products:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Trends</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/intelligence/market-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/intelligence/market-trends/</guid>
      <description>The Market Trends is a collection of trade lanes and corridors available for quick review. It features rate price information for today&amp;rsquo;s date and a selectable date in the past, along with a small graph that shows the general trend for the trade lane for a selected period.
 It contains two tabs:
Rate Movements
This view allows you to see how market rates have changed for different periods up to a year back in time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Prices</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/myprices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/myprices/</guid>
      <description>The My Prices page collects your air freight rates and organizes them into a number of categories for convenient analysis. Overview For an in-depth look at the My Prices page in Xeneta for Air Freight, read our help article. The My Prices page lists every rate you&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded into Xeneta. It contains a number of filters — including transit time, weight break, and service type — to help you find the rates relevant to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Off-Tender Requests</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/off-tender-requests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/off-tender-requests/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Every organization has a different approach to tenders — some tender frequently, others only once a year. However, if your freight needs change outside of the usual tender period, it may be cumbersome or expensive for your organization to begin making price requests for additional freight.
With Xeneta, you can instantly find spot prices for any trade lane globally — without going through a back-and-forth with potential suppliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spend Analysis</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/analytics/spend-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/analytics/spend-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Overview Spend Analysis uses your uploaded volume data to calculate estimated savings and theoretical market spend in dollars.
Spend Comparison The Spend Comparison — available on the Analytics dashboard — helps you compare the price you paid for your volume you have shipped against shipping the same volume at different market prices. The Spend Comparison panel compares your spend volume to the market low, average, and high spends.
Example: If you ship 100 TEU at $100 each, the value of My Covered Spend will be $10,000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/uploading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/uploading/</guid>
      <description>One of the core features of the Xeneta platform is the ability to benchmark your rates against the market. Benchmarking is another way of saying &amp;ldquo;comparing&amp;rdquo; — that is, you compare the prices you pay for shipping against other market participants as a whole.
Benchmarking can help you understand how much you pay relative to the market and can, in turn, give you the insight you need to negotiate better rates in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Excel for Benchmarking</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll take a look at working with Excel to look at Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s Benchmarking data by exploring a few basic examples. Introduction Xeneta can export the data that composes the Benchmarks graph to an Excel report.
To begin, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to generate the Benchmarks graph for the trade lane or trade corridor whose data we wish to export. Use the dashboard search or your followed trade lanes to reach the Benchmarks graph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Horizon</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/concepts/futures/</guid>
      <description>At its core, the Xeneta platform helps you understand the trends in the freight market. It does so by providing three views of the market:
 The historical rate trends The current day&amp;rsquo;s rate The trends of rates that run into the future or begin in the future  In the third case, Xeneta offers a short view of the future by showing contracted freight rates that extend past the current day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphs</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/graphs/</guid>
      <description>Graphs are a tool for visualizing your freight rates in relation to the market and your own freight forwarders. Overview Xeneta for Air Freight uses the Benchmarks graph to plot both market prices and your freight forwarder prices together. It has a number of filters to help you narrow the scope of the rates you&amp;rsquo;re viewing, including filters for date range, weight break, and service level.
 The Benchmarks graph helps you compare the rates you pay for your freight forwarders against the market at large across specific trade lanes or broader regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Rates Beyond Today</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</guid>
      <description>In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the Contract Horizon feature to examine where the freight market is trending past the present day. Introduction The Xeneta platform provides market trends and benchmarks based on current and historical freight rates. Of course, in the cycle of freight procurement and contract negotiation, new shipping contracts are always being established.
In these cases, the contracts negotiated near the present day may be contracted to start a few weeks or months in the future — but they are still signed today and reflect today&amp;rsquo;s market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Your Market Position</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/understand-market-position/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/understand-market-position/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The first step to improving your freight contracts is understanding where they stand in relation to the market. By uploading your freight rates into Xeneta, you can leverage Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s benchmarking capabilities to find out where you can improve your freight rates.
The Spend Overview The Spend Overview collects all of your uploaded freight rates and breaks them down by corridor. It is immediately useful for finding the corridors with the largest spend and the largest volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Supplier Performance</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/measure-supplier-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/measure-supplier-performance/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Xeneta can organize your uploaded data by individual suppliers, which will let you identify your best and worst performing suppliers.
Supplier Breakdown You can see the volume, spend, and saving potentials of all of your suppliers by navigating to the Suppliers tab of the Spend Overview.
 View example in Xeneta  The Covered vs. Market column indicates the level to which your rates are above or below the market for the same trade lanes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/release-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/release-notes/</guid>
      <description>May 14, 2020Followed Market Trends RefreshOceanFeature ReleaseThe Market Trends page has been redesigned and now includes graphs to visualize market movements for your followed trade lanes up to a year back in time.
For more details on this feature, read our documentation.
 March 2, 2020Export Graph to ImageOceanAirFeature ReleaseYou can now export the Benchmarks and Trends graphs to a PNG image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benchmark Against Peers</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/benchmark-against-peers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/benchmark-against-peers/</guid>
      <description>By default, Xeneta offers benchmarking against the entire ocean freight market.
As an additional service, Xeneta provides industry-based benchmarking so that you can compare your performance specifically to others in your industry.
 This service is part of a larger reporting suite called Executive Reporting. Executive Reporting includes deeper analysis into your freight data including competitive analysis, regional performance, and carrier performance.
Contact your Customer Success Manager to learn more about Executive Reporting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Duration Consideration</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/contract-duration-consideration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/contract-duration-consideration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As markets develop and react to economic circumstances, it is important to be aware of all your tendering options. With Xeneta you can
You could reasonably forecast that locking in a long-term contract at current rate levels would be undesirable.
A Look at Long-term Contracts Consider the following historical trend for long-term contracts from 20-10-2018  to 20-10-2020  on the China East Main to North Europe Main:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Budget Expectations</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/set-budget-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/use-cases/set-budget-expectations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s important to set your budget as you go into tender. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been out of the market for some time, Xeneta can help you align expectations and forecast possible budget increases or decreases.
Global Market Trends You can use the Global Market Trends to see corridor price changes between the present day and up to a year in the past.
 View example in Xeneta  By setting the Display parameter to the Past 1 Year, you can quickly find how the corridors that are relevant to your organization have been impacted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>