<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xeneta Guide</title>
    <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xeneta Guide</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://guide.xeneta.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/overview/</guid>
      <description>The Ocean dashboard summarizes your freight spend information and provides a search box for finding market prices for trade lanes. Overview The Ocean dashboard ties together all the key pieces of information about your freight spend in a single page. It&amp;rsquo;s a good starting point for understanding your position in the freight market.
Once you have the basics down, you can use the dashboard to quickly navigate to deeper analytics provided by Xeneta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide 1</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide1/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s platform offers you a number of tools to help you understand the freight market. Here you can find some basic use cases for the Xeneta platform. Ocean Words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Freight Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/introfreightrate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/introfreightrate/</guid>
      <description>An Introduction to Freight Rate Benchmarking and Analytics for Ocean Freight What is a freight rate? A freight rate is a negotiated price for shipping a freight container from one part of the world to another.
Freight rates that are tied to contracts have a validity period that defines the length of time that the freight rate is valid. The validity of a freight rate will depend on if it is based on a short-term contract or a long-term contract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/overview/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta for Air Freight is an analytics and benchmark platform for understanding the prices of the air freight market. The Dashboard For details about Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s benchmarking of air freight, read our this article. Like the Ocean dashboard, the Air freight dashboard contains a port-to-port search bar and a summary of your price coverage and price benchmarks.
Dashboard — Xeneta for Air Freight The Port-to-port Search The port-to-port search on the dashboard is used to find spot rates for air freight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide 2</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide2/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta can create a number of Excel reports based on the analytics data found on our platform.
Any page capable of exporting an Excel report will contain a  symbol in the top-right corner of the page. You can find all your created reports on the Reports page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Metrics</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/marketmetrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/marketmetrics/</guid>
      <description>For an in-depth look at Market Metrics, read our article in the help center. Market metrics are a set of options that control how freight rate data is displayed in Xeneta. You can think of them as a global-level filters for rate information.
They appear in the top-right corner of on any pages capable of showing freight data — including Air and Ocean dashboards.
Market metrics for ocean freight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Prices</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/myprices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/myprices/</guid>
      <description>The My Prices page collects your air freight rates and organizes them into a number of categories for convenient analysis. Overview For an in-depth look at the My Prices page in Xeneta for Air Freight, read our help article. The My Prices page lists every rate you&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded into Xeneta. It contains a number of filters — including transit time, weight break, and service type — to help you find the rates relevant to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/portsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/portsearch/</guid>
      <description>The port-to-port search allows you to find today&amp;rsquo;s rate for the majority of port-to-port combinations in the world across a variety of container types. Overview The port-to-port search bar can be found on the dashboard and at the top of any graphs pages.
The port-to-port search with a result. Simply enter an origin port and a destination port, select your preferred container type, and click Search.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploading Rates</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/uploading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/uploading/</guid>
      <description>One of the core features of the Xeneta platform is the ability to benchmark your rates against the market. Benchmarking is another way of saying &amp;ldquo;comparing&amp;rdquo; — that is, you compare the prices you pay for shipping against other market participants as a whole.
Benchmarking can help you understand how much you pay relative to the market and can, in turn, give you the insight you need to negotiate better rates in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract Horizon</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/futures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/concepts/futures/</guid>
      <description>At its core, the Xeneta platform helps you understand the trends in the freight market. It does so by providing three views of the market:
 The historical rate trends The current day&amp;rsquo;s rate The trend of rates that run into the future or begin in the future  In the third case, Xeneta offers a short view of the future by showing contracted freight rates that extend past the current day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphs</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/air/graphs/</guid>
      <description>Graphs are a tool for visualizing your freight rates in relation to the market and your own freight forwarders. Overview Xeneta for Air Freight uses the Benchmarks graph to plot both market prices and your freight forwarder prices together. It has a number of filters to help you narrow the scope of the rates you&amp;rsquo;re viewing, including filters for date range, weight break, and service level.
The Benchmarks graph for air freight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide 3</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/guides/guide3/</guid>
      <description>One of the core features of the Xeneta platform is the ability to benchmark your rates against the market. Benchmarking is another way of saying &amp;ldquo;comparing&amp;rdquo; — that is, you compare the prices you pay for shipping against other market participants as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Prices</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/myprices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/myprices/</guid>
      <description>The My Prices page organizes your uploaded freight rates into a number of categories to help you understand your prices across the market. Overview The My Prices page lists every rate you’ve uploaded into Xeneta. It contains a number of filters — including origin, destination, supplier, and container type — to help you find the rates relevant to you.
The My Prices page. My Prices functionality is only available if you&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded your freight rates into Xeneta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/gettingstarted/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/gettingstarted/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta&amp;rsquo;s platform offers you a number of tools to help you understand the freight market. Here you can find some basic use cases for the Xeneta platform. Ocean View a summary of your freight ratesUse the dashboard to get an overview of your rates and how they compare to the market. Get a spot rate for a trade laneUse the trade lane search from the dashboard to retrieve today&amp;#39;s market rates for any origin and destination port across a number of container types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/introduction/reports/</guid>
      <description>Xeneta can create a number of Excel reports based on the analytics data found on our platform.
Any page capable of exporting an Excel report will contain a  symbol in the top-right corner of the page. You can find all your created reports on the Reports page.
Note: A number of larger reports will take some time to generate. In such cases, you&amp;rsquo;ll be notified by email when your report is ready.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spend Overview</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/spendoverview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/spendoverview/</guid>
      <description>The Spend Overview page ties together your freight volume and its associated prices with the rest of the market. Overview For an in-depth look at the Spend Overview page, read our help center article. The Spend Overview helps you understand how much your freight prices can improve in terms of dollar value. Xeneta refers to this as the Saving Potential — the theoretical savings that can be achieved if the prices you paid for freight matched the price paid by different segments of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphs</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/graphs/</guid>
      <description>Graphs are a tool for visualizing your freight rates in relation to the market and your own suppliers. Overview Xeneta provides three types of graphs to help you understand your rates:
 The Benchmarks graph The Trends graph The Carrier Spread graph  All graphs in Xeneta have a number of filters to help you narrow the scope of the rates you&amp;rsquo;re viewing, including filters for date range, container type, contract duration, and terminal handling charges (THC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API</title>
      <link>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guide.xeneta.com/ocean/api/</guid>
      <description>The Xeneta API can be used to work with rate information programmatically. For more information about getting API access, read this article.
See the API reference for technical details.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>